Guide to the William Graham Sumner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1854-(1863-1909)-1948; Series I; 14' (36 boxes)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Egleston, Melville - E. Elliott, 1870, 1873, 1875, 1881-1882, 1884, 1903-1904, 1909, undated (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Elliott, Frederic B. (*), 1870-1871, 1872 March - 1873 Dec, 1874 February - 1877 November, 1878 November - 1879 Dec, 1880 May - 1881 Dec, 1882-1883, 1882 January - 1883 November, 1883 January - 1885 November, 1886 January - 1886 November (Box 7, Folder 183-192)
    - Elliott, Frederic B. (*), 1887 April - 1890 Nov, 1891, 1895, 1898, 1899, 1900 April - 1900 Nov, 1901-1903, 1906, undated (Box 8, Folder 193-199)
    - Elliott, Henry H. (*), 1870-1884, 1887-1899, 1901, 1903, 1904, 1906, undated (Box 8, Folder 200-204)
    - Elliott, H. - John Elliott, 1871, 1895, 1907-1908 (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Elliott, Julia (*), 1870, 1882, 1889, 1900, undated (Box 8, Folder 206-209)
    - Elliott, L. R. - Emerson Publishing Company, 1869, 1873, 1875, 1878, 1885, 1887, 1891, 1897, 1903, 1907, undated (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Emerson, N. B. - Carl E. Epler, 1870, 1873, 1883, 1886, 1889, 1896-1897, 1900, 1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - Equal Rights Debating Club - R. D. Evans, 1881, 1884-1885, 1890, 1899, 1904, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Evening Post, 1883, undated (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Everit, R. M. - George B. Farnam, 1877, 1883-1884, 1887, 1896-1899, 1907-1909, undated (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Farnam, Henry W. (*), 1883-1888 (Box 8, Folder 215-216)
      See also: box 5, folder 107
    - Farnam, Henry W. (*), 1889-1908 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Farnam, William H. - Henry Fawcett, 1869-1870, 1877, 1886-1887, 1890, 1895, 1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Felton, George - W. T. Fields, 1870-1871, 1873, 1875, 1881, 1883-1885, 1889, 1896-1897, 1899, 1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - Filipino Students' Magazine - Henry W. Fischer, 1873-1874, 1876, 1878, 1883, 1886, 1895, 1898-1899, 1906 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Fisher, Irving (*), 1885-1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 221-222)
    - Fisher, Laura - T. F. Fitzgerald, 1875, 1877-1880, 1888, 1890, 1897, 1908, undated (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Flanders, Henry - Lozelle Foote, 1873, 1881, 1883-1884, 1887, 1889, 1891, 1897, undated (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - Ford, C. W. - Henry A. Ford, 1876, 1880, 1884, 1890, 1898, 1908 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - Ford, Paul L. - William F. Ford, 1880-1881, 1884-1885, 1890-1891, 1893, 1897-1899 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Ford, Worthington C. (*), 1880-1883, 1885-1893, undated (Box 9, Folder 227-228)
      See also: box 3, folder 60
      See also: Van Buren Denslow
    - Forman, B. R. - Kate Foster, 1864, 1872, 1877-1878, 1881, 1883-1884, 1886, 1903, undated (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Forman, B. R.
    - Foster, Roger (*), 1878, 1881-1883, 1886, 1895-1896; See also: box 17, folder 467 (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Foster, W. Frederic - H. G. Fowler, 1874, 1876, 1883-1886, 1888, 1896, 1899, undated (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Fowler, Horace (*), 1870-1886 (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - Fowler, John S. - George H. Fox, 1875, 1877, 1893, 1899, undated (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Fox, George L. - T. J. Fox, 1875, 1883, 1886-1887, 1890-1891, 1899, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 234)
    - Francis, David G. - Free Trade Congressional Committee, 1869, 1880-1883, 1885-1886, 1888, 1890, undated (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - Freehoff, Joe - Fuller, Lord and Company, 1869-1870, 1872, 1876, 1881-1885, 1887-1888, 1890, 1896, undated (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - Fuller, George W. - Otto W. Futterer, 1874, 1879-1880, 1883-1884, 1886-1887, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - Gabriel, J. H. - George P. Garrison, 1875-1876, 1881-1882, 1885-1887, 1889, 1895-1896, 1900, 1903, undated (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Garrison, W. P. (*), 1873-1874, 1878-1883, 1885, 1893, undated (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd, 1879, 1904, 1906, 1908 (Box 9, Folder 240)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd
      See: American Free Trade League, box 1, folder 11
    - Garuan, P. - F. A. Gilbert, 1874-1875, 1877-1879, 1883-1888, 1895-1898, 1904, 1909, undated (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Gilder, Joseph B. (*), 1882-1884, 1886, 1897 (Box 9, Folder 242)
      See also: box 9, folder 227-228
    - S. Gildersleeves and Sons - J. A. Gilson, 1876, 1879, 1882, 1884, 1889-1890, 1897, 1900, 1909, undated (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - Ginn and Company (*), 1886, 1889, 1906-1908 (Box 9, Folder 244)
    - Gitterman, Alice - John C. Goddard, 1878, 1883, 1887, 1896, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 245)
    - Godkin, Edwin L. (*), 1870-1890, undated (Box 9, Folder 246-248)
    - Godkin, Fanny - F. A. Gooch, 1868, 1870, 1873, 1875-1876, 1887, 1897-1898, 1900, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 249)
    - Good Cheer - J. Graham, 1870, 1875-1876, 1878, 1885, 1887, 1889, 1893, 1897, 1904, undated (Box 9, Folder 250)
    - Graham, Kate - Mary Graham, 1866, 1869, 1882, undated (Box 9, Folder 251)
    - Graham, Thomas A., 1881, 1884, undated (Box 9, Folder 252)
    - Graham, V. K. - Mary Gray, 1869, 1873, 1879, 1884, 1886, 1891, 1893, 1895, 1900, 1903, undated (Box 9, Folder 253)
    - Graybill, James Edward (*), 1876, 1880, 1884, 1898, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 254)
    - Green, Alfred W. - William Greene, 1870, 1872, 1876, 1878, 1881, 1883-1885, 1889, 1893-1895, 1897-1898, undated (Box 9, Folder 255)
    - Greenough, W. P. - C. E. W. Grinnell, 1870, 1879-1880, 1883-1884, 1890, 1893, 1895-1896, 1906, undated (Box 10, Folder 256)
    - Grinnell, Charles E. (*), 1865-1879, 1881-1888, 1890-1897, 1900-1908 (Box 10, Folder 257-269)
    - Grinnell, Charles E. Letter fragments (*), (1860's) (Box 10, Folder 270)
    - Grinnell, Charles E., undated (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - Grinnell, Elizabeth W. - Gustav Gruener, 1875, 1877-1878, 1886, 1889-1891, 1893, 1897-1898, 1901, 1908, undated (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - Guernsey, Nathaniel- G. H. Gurnee, 1876, 1882-1883, 1886, 1888, 1893, undated (Box 10, Folder 273)
    - Guyot, Yves (*), 1886, 1889, 1891, 1903-1904 (Box 10, Folder 274)
    - Hadley, Arthur T. (*), 1886-1888, 1890-1891, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 275)
    - Hadden, W. R. - Joseph Hall, 1876, 1880, 1882-1886, 1888, 1891, 1898-1899, undated (Box 10, Folder 276)
    - Hall, U. S. - Charles D. Hamel, 1876, 1882, 1885, 1890, 1892, 1903 (Box 10, Folder 277)
    - Hamersley, Sophia (*), undated (Box 10, Folder 278)
    - Hamersley, William - Henry Hammond, 1873-1874, 1876, 1881-1882, 1884-1885, 1890, 1895-1896, 1899-1900, 1904, undated (Box 10, Folder 279)
    - Hancock, J. D. - Lewis C. Harley, 1875, 1877, 1882, 1884-1888, 1900, undated (Box 10, Folder 280)
    - Harper and Brothers (*), 1872, 1883-1895 (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - Harper, W. A. - L. D. Harris, 1869-1870, 1900, 1906, 1908-1909 (Box 10, Folder 282)
    - Harrison, Burton N. (*), 1868-1869, 1872, 1874, undated (Box 10, Folder 283)
    - Harrison, Constance Cary - William E. Hart, 1876, 1883, 1886, 1890, 1896, 1900-1901, 1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 284)
    - Harter, M. D. - George B. Harvey, 1879-1883,1885-1886, 1890, 1892, 1898, 1900, 1902, undated (Box 11, Folder 285)
    - Harwood, E. (*), 1868-1869, 1872, 1878-1879, undated (Box 11, Folder 286)
    - Harwood, M. - I. L. Hauser, 1869, 1872, 1881, 1883-1885, 1890-1891, 1899- 1900, undated (Box 11, Folder 287)
    - Hawk and Wetherbee - W. R. Hearst, 1876-1879, 1882, 1887-1888, 1890, 1895-1897, 1899, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 288)
    - Heath, B. S. - R. C. Helfenstein, 1869, 1872-1874, 1876, 1879, 1883, 1889-1890, 1892-1893, 1895, 1897-1899, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 289)
    - Hellings, W. P. - C. S. Henry, 1869-1871, 1875-1876, 1880, 1882, 1884, 1887-1889, 1894-1895, undated (Box 11, Folder 290)
    - Henry, F. A. - E. Heywood, 1870, 1872, 1878, 1888, 1895, 1904, undated (Box 11, Folder 291)
    - Hickox, J. H. (*), 1886-1890, 1893, 1895-1896, undated (Box 11, Folder 292)
    - Hicks, Everett - N. L. Higginson and Company, 1882, 1884-1885, 1888, 1890, 1894, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 293)
    - Hildreth, J. L. - Mary Hine, 1875-1878, 1881, 1883-1888, 1891, 1897, 1907, undated (Box 11, Folder 294)
    - Hine, Charles (*), 1883 January - 1883 Dec, 1884-1892, 1893 January - October (Box 11, Folder 295-305)
    - Hine, Charles, 1893 November - December (Box 11, Folder 306)
    - Hine, Charles (*), 1895 January - 1895 May, 1895 July - 1895 Nov, 1896-1898 (Box 12, Folder 307-311)
    - Hine, Charles, 1899 (Box 12, Folder 312)
    - Hine, Charles (*), 1900, 1901 February - 1901 Nov, 1903 January - 1903 Dec, 1904, 1906-1908, undated (Box 12, Folder 313-322)
    - Hine, O. C. - H. Z. Hitter, 1877-1879, 1881-1886, 1890, 1892, 1903, undated (Box 12, Folder 323)
    - Hine, O. C.
      See: box 11, folder 295-305
    - Hinrichs, Fred W.
    - Hoadly, Carrie - N. D. C. Hodges, 1863, 1879, 1886, 1895, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 324)
    - Hoepi, Ulrico - F. Holden, 1869, 1874, 1876, 1881, 1888, 1897, 1899-1901, 1904, undated (Box 12, Folder 325)
    - Holding, A. M. - Hamilton Holt, 1869, 1873-1874, 1878, 1880, 1883-1885, 1889-1890, 1899-1901, 1903, 1908 (Box 12, Folder 326)
    - Holt, Henry (*), 1872-1876, 1879-1884 (Box 12, Folder 327-329)
    - Holt, Henry (*), 1885-1886 (Box 13, Folder 330)
    - Holt, Henry (*), 1887-1908 (Box 13, Folder 331)
    - Holt, L. H. - W. E. Hooker, 1879-1880, 1883, 1885, 1887, 1889, 1893, 1895-1898, 1902-1903, 1908, undated (Box 13, Folder 332)
    - Hopkins, Archibald (*), 1870-1877, 1881-1885, undated (Box 13, Folder 333-336)
    - Hopkins, E. Washburn - George W. Hotchkiss, 1874, 1877-1878, 1882, 1884, 1890, 1893, 1897 1899, 1904, 1908, undated (Box 13, Folder 337)
    - Houghton, Mifflin and Company (*), 1882-1908 (Box 13, Folder 338-339)
    - Houghton, H. O. - W. D. Howells, 1866, 1873-1874, 1884-1886, 1888, 1890-1891, 1893, 1908, undated (Box 13, Folder 340)
    - Howland, Louis (*), 1876, 1884, 1885, 1900,1908, undated (Box 13, Folder 341)
    - Howrison, C. H. - F. M. Hoyt, 1887, 1897, undated (Box 13, Folder 342)
    - Hoyt, Geraldine - Gertrude Hoyt, undated (Box 13, Folder 343)
    - Hoyt, Henry M., Jr. (*), 1880-1887 (Box 13, Folder 344)
    - Hoyt, Henry M. - Woodward Hudson, 1870, 1880-1881, 1884-1885, 1891, 1895, 1900, 1908, undated (Box 13, Folder 345)
    - Hulbet, William Henry - Samuel H. Huntington, 1869, 1872, 1876-1877, 1883-1885, 1899, 1901, 1909, undated (Box 13, Folder 346)
    - Huntington, Samuel (*), 1864-1908 (Box 13, Folder 347)
    - Huntington, W. R. - William Hyde, 1869-1870, 1872-1873, 1880, 1883-1884, 1886, 1888, 1890, 1893, 1898, 1901, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 13, Folder 348)
    - Ide, George Edward - Illustrated Christian World, 1874, 1881, 1888-1890 (Box 13, Folder 349)
    - The Independent, 1883, 1886, 1891 (Box 13, Folder 350)
    - Independent Republican Association - Henry J. Ingersoll, 1876, 1880, 1883-1885, 1890, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 351)
    - Ingersoll, J. W. D. - Iroquois Club, 1877, 1885-1886, 1888, 1890-1891, 1900, 1904, 1906-1908 (Box 13, Folder 352)
    - Irvine, James E. - Theo. W. Ivory, 1870, 1872, 1874-1875, 1877-1878, 1882-1883, 1897, 1904, undated (Box 13, Folder 353)
    - Jackson, C. C. - W. K. James, 1869, 1879, 1882-1886, 1889-1890, 1897, 1899-1890, 1908, undated (Box 13, Folder 354)
    - Jameson, J. F. (*), 1891-1900 (Box 14, Folder 355)
    - Jay, Peter A. - John J. Jennings, 1869, 1873-1874, 1883-1886, 1895, 1904, 1906 (Box 14, Folder 356)
    - Jesup, Morris K. - J. E. Johnson, 1872-1873, 1875, 1884, 1889, 1900, 1904, 1908, undated (Box 14, Folder 357)
    - Johnson, J. J. - Joliet Public Library, 1874, 1876, 1878-1883, 1885, 1887, 1889, 1897-1898, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 14, Folder 358)
    - Jones, Frank - Richard Lloyd Jones, 1870, 1872-1873, 1876, 1878, 1881-1882, 1885, 1887, 1903-1904, undated (Box 14, Folder 359)
    - Jordan, David - Charles A. Joy, 1876, 1877, 1881-1883, 1885, 1893, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 360)
    - Judd and White - Albert F. Judd, 1872-1874, 1877, 1879, 1880, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 361)
    - Judd, Edward P.(*), 1878, 1880, 1882, 1890, 1893, 1895, 1898-1899, 1901, 1903, 1906, undated (Box 14, Folder 362)
    - Judd, John S. (*), 1889, 1889 October - 1890 September (Box 14, Folder 363-364)
    - Judd, Susan (*), 1883 (Box 14, Folder 365)
    - Judson, Frederick N. (*), 1867-1873 (Box 14, Folder 366)
    - Judson, Frederick N., 1875-1903 (Box 14, Folder 367)
    - Judson, John N. - John F. Keator, 1872-1874, 1877, 1884, 1892, 1895, 1897, 1904, 1907, 1908, undated (Box 14, Folder 368)
    - Keeler, John E. - William Kellock, 1863, 1877, 1886, 1889, 1895, 1896, undated (Box 14, Folder 369)
    - Keller, Albert G. (*), 1896-1901 (Box 14, Folder 370-371)
    - Keller, Albert G., 1903-1906 (Box 14, Folder 372)
    - Keller, Albert G. (*), 1908 January - 1908 Oct, 1909 January - 1909 Sep, undated (Box 14, Folder 373-377)
    - Kellogg, D. O. (*), 1869-1875 (Box 14, Folder 378)
    - Kelly, D. D. - B. F. Kemp, 1869, 1877, 1880, 1882, 1884, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 379)
    - Kemp, Henry (*), 1876-1880 (Box 14, Folder 380)
    - Kempfer, J. T. - John A. Keppellman, 1881-1882, 1885-1886, 1888, 1893, 1896-1899, 1901, 1903, 1906, undated (Box 14, Folder 381)
    - Kernochan, J. Frederic (*), 1863-1866, 1869-1872 (Box 14, Folder 382-383)
    - Kernochan, J. Frederic (*), 1875-1883 (Box 15, Folder 384)
    - Kernochan, J. Frederic (*), 1884-1908 (Box 15, Folder 385)
    - Kernochan, Mary - F. J. Kingsbury, 1876, 1881, 1884-1885, 1890, 1898-1901, undated (Box 15, Folder 386)
    - Kinney, Herbert E. - Charles A. Klots, 1872, 1875-1876, 1879-1881, 1883, 1885, 1890, 1900, 1903, 1906-1907 (Box 15, Folder 387)
    - Knapp, F. B. - N. D. Knupp, 1869, 1877, 1882-1885, 1890, 1892, 1906 (Box 15, Folder 388)
    - Koehler, K. F. (*), 1887-1906 (Box 15, Folder 389-391)
    - Koffond, Joe, Jr. - S. G. Kusworne, 1869, 1884, 1886, 1892, 1895, 1897, 1908, undated (Box 15, Folder 392)
    - Ladd, G. T. - W. C. Lake, 1873-1875, 1884, 1886, 1889, undated (Box 15, Folder 393)
    - Lalor, John J. (*), 1878, 1881, 1883 (Box 15, Folder 394)
    - Lamberson Jay G. - Charles Lark, 1871, 1876-1877, 1881, 1885-1888, 1899, 1908 (Box 15, Folder 395)
    - Larned, E. C. - Joseph E. Lauber, 1891, 1893, 1903, undated (Box 15, Folder 396)
    - Laughlin, J. Laurence (*), 1883-1897 (Box 15, Folder 397)
    - Lave, C. F. - William Lawrence, 1876-1877, 1884-1885 (Box 15, Folder 398)
    - Lawrence, W. B. (*), 1882-1890 (Box 15, Folder 399)
    - Lea, John - Leeds Company, 1869, 1880, 1882-1883, 1886-1887, 1892, 1900-1901, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 15, Folder 400)
    - Leete, Charles H. - C. H. Leonard, 1875-1876, 1878, 1881-1883, 1885-1887 (Box 15, Folder 401)
    - Leonard, Emily J. - E. H. Libbey, 1875, 1878, 1883-1884, 1889, 1893, 1899, 1900, undated (Box 15, Folder 402)
    - Libbey, Jonas (*), 1877-1884 (Box 15, Folder 403-404)
    - Libbey, William - R. P. Lincoln, 1875, 1879-1884, 1889-1890, 1904, undated (Box 15, Folder 405)
    - Lindsay, Fred N. - Thales Lindsay, 1882, 1890, 1895, 1900, 1906, undated (Box 15, Folder 406)
    - Lippincott, J. A. - E. S. Lives, 1872-1873, 1880-1881, 1886-1887 (Box 15, Folder 407)
    - Living Church, undated (Box 15, Folder 408)
    - Livingston, Claude - John C. Lloyd, 1882, 1886-1887, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 409)
    - Lobdell, Francis - Longman's, Green and Company, 1872-1874, 1876, 1879-1890, 1882-1883, 1885, 1890-1891, 1897, 1904, undated (Box 15, Folder 410)
    - Loois, David - James Lowell, 1873-1874, 1878, 1883, 1887-1888, 1890, 1897, 1899, 1903, 1907, undated (Box 15, Folder 411)
    - Luce, Robert L. (*), 1891-1903 (Box 15, Folder 412)
    - N. Luchting and Company - F. C. Lyman, 1866, 1875, 1877, 1879, 1884-1885, 1897, undated (Box 15, Folder 413)
    - Lyman, Hart - May B. Lyon, 1887, 1897-1898, 1907-1908, undated (Box 15, Folder 414)
    - McAdam, Graham (*), 1879-1883 (Box 16, Folder 415)
    - McAllister, J. C. - Harry McCauley, 1880, 1884, 1886, 1889, 1896, 1898, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 416)
    - McCleary, J. T. - Joseph A. McDonald, 1875-1879, 1882, 1886-1887, 1891, 1895-1896, 1898, 1900, 1904, 1906-1908, undated (Box 16, Folder 417)
    - Mace, William S. - John McKee, 1867, 1869, 1876, 1880, 1884, 1887, 1891, undated (Box 16, Folder 418)
    - McKeever, J. Lawrence (*), 1872-1874, 1880, 1882-1883, 1889-1891, 1895-1896, 1898 (Box 16, Folder 419)
      See also: London and Brazilian Bank, Ltd., box 15, folder 410
    - Mackens, Rosie - G. T. McMaster, 1869, 1874, 1877, 1883, 1888-1889, 1893, 1900 (Box 16, Folder 420)
    - Macmillan and Company (*), 1872, 1895-1897, 1901, 1903-1904, 1906-1908 (Box 16, Folder 421)
    - McMillan, D. C. - V. F. McNeil, 1868, 1876, 1878, 1887, 1898, 1900, 1903, 1906, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 422)
    - McNulty, Albert (*), 1879-1889 (Box 16, Folder 423)
    - Macoane, S. M. - Frank McVey, 1866, 1877, 1879, 1884, 1888-1890, 1893, 1895, 1901, undated (Box 16, Folder 424)
    - MacWhorter, Alexander, 1869-1875 (Box 16, Folder 425)
    - Maddox, E. L. - M. S. Mandell, 1874, 1883-1885, 1887-1888, 1890, 1893, 1900-1901, 1903, 1906, 1909, undated (Box 16, Folder 426)
    - Manderson, Charles F. - H. W. Mansfield, 1869, 1878, 1881, 1884, 1887, 1891, 1895, 1898-1899, 1906-1907, undated (Box 16, Folder 427)
    - Mansfield, Howard (*), 1873, 1875, 1877, 1879-1880, 1891, undated (Box 16, Folder 428)
    - Mansfield, May - O. C. Marsh, 1876, 1881, 1884-1887, 1890, 1897-1899, 1901, 1908, undated (Box 16, Folder 429)
    - Marsh, W. L. - G. Mase, 1874, 1876-1877, 1881, 1884, 1895, undated (Box 16, Folder 430)
    - Mason, Alfred Bishop (*), 1875-1880, 1882, 1885, 1890, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 431-433)
    - Mason, E. G. - Massachusetts Reform Club, 1869-1870, 1874, 1880, 1885-1887, 1899, 1901, 1903, undated (Box 16, Folder 434)
    - Massachusetts Tariff Reform League (*), 1884-1891 (Box 16, Folder 435)
      See also: New England Tariff Reform League, box 17, folder 466
    - Massey, Benjamin - Robert Mathews, 1877, 1880, 1883-1886, 1888 (Box 16, Folder 436)
    - Maxwell, John - Effingham Maynard and Company, 1875, 1880-1881, 1885, 1888, 1890, 1897, undated (Box 16, Folder 437)
    - Mead, Edward S. (*), 1890-1891 (Box 16, Folder 438)
    - Mead, Fred, Jr. - L. P. Mercer, 1872, 1875-1877, 1880, 1883, 1886-1887, 1893, 1899-1901, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 16, Folder 439)
    - Meriwether, Avery - Alice M. Merriam, 1871-1872, 1878-1879, 1881, 1883, 1885, 1887, 1895-1898, 1900-1901, 1904, 1908, undated (Box 16, Folder 440)
    - Merriman, Elias P. - H. C. Metcalf, 1874, 1878, 1882, 1897-1899, 1901, 1903, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 16, Folder 441)
    - Metcalf, L. S. (*), 1882-1889, undated (Box 16, Folder 442)
    - Metcalf, William T. - Francis T. Miller, 1865-1866, 1876, 1878, 1881, 1883-1884, 1887-1889, 1896, 1899, 1901, 1904, 1906 (Box 16, Folder 443)
    - Miller, George D. (*), 1869-1904 (Box 17, Folder 444)
    - Miller, Henry W. - The Million, 1875, 1882, 1885, 1897-1899, undated (Box 17, Folder 445)
    - Mills, Abraham (*), 1874-1896, undated (Box 17, Folder 446)
    - Mills, J. J. - Solomon Minor, 1873, 1887, 1896, undated (Box 17, Folder 447)
    - Minturn, R. B. (*), 1875-1884 (Box 17, Folder 448)
    - Missionary Relief Association - Walter Mitchell, 1869-1870, 1873, 1875-1876, 1883-1885, 1897, undated (Box 17, Folder 449)
    - N. B. Mix and Son - Frank G. Moore, 1875, 1883-1888, 1891, 1903-1904, undated (Box 17, Folder 450)
    - Moore, Frederick W. (*), 1880, 1889-1891 (Box 17, Folder 451)
    - Moore, Henry H. - Arthur B. Morrill, 1874-1875, 1877, 1880, 1883, 1885, 1889-1890, 1893, 1896, 1899, 1903, 1906, 1908 (Box 17, Folder 452)
    - Morrill, F. L. - Bushrod Morse, 1873, 1876, 1879-1885, 1890-1891, 1897, 1899, 1901, undated (Box 17, Folder 453)
    - Morse, John T., Jr. (*), 1881-1882 (Box 17, Folder 454)
    - Morse, Richard C. - Alice J. Mott, 1879-1881, 1883, 1885-1887, 1890, 1897, 1900, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 17, Folder 455)
    - Mott, Henry P. (*), 1875-1877 (Box 17, Folder 456)
    - Moulton, A. A. - Walter Myers, 1879-1881, 1886-1887, 1889, 1896-1897, 1900-1901, 1903, 1907-1909, undated (Box 17, Folder 457)
    - Nash, E. W. - H. S. Nash, 1880, 1882, 1886, undated (Box 17, Folder 458)
    - Nation, undated (Box 17, Folder 459)
    - National Association of Anti-Imperialist Clubs - National Civic Federation, 1872, 1898, 1904, 1906, 1908 (Box 17, Folder 460)
    - National Civil Service Reform League - National Silver Convention, 1876, 1884, 1897, 1899, 1903-1904, 1908, undated (Box 17, Folder 461)
    - National Tradesmen Bank (*), 1887-1908 (Box 17, Folder 462)
    - Naylor, L. W. - T. H. Nevin, 1873, 1884-1885, 1889, 1895-1896, 1903-1904, undated (Box 17, Folder 463)
    - New England Anti-Imperialist League (*), 1899-1903 (Box 17, Folder 464)
    - New England Free Trade League (*), 1897-1900 (Box 17, Folder 465)
    - New England Labor Reform League - New York Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor, 1885, 1890, 1904, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 17, Folder 466)
    - New York Free Trade Club (*), 1878-1886, undated (Box 17, Folder 467)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Rail Road Company - John S. Newbold, 1869, 1871, 1880, 1882-1883, 1885, 1890, 1897-1899 (Box 17, Folder 468)
    - Newcomb, Simon (*), 1884-1886 (Box 17, Folder 469)
    - Newell, John - H. A. Newton, 1874, 1878, 1882-1883, 1885, 1888, 1891, 1900-1901, undated (Box 17, Folder 470)
    - Newton, Henry G. - Henry P. Nichols, 1869, 1879, 1884-1888, 1893, 1896, 1901, 1903, undated (Box 17, Folder 471)
    - Nichols, S. H. - Harry E. Nolan, 1877, 1883, 1886, 1890, 1901-1904, 1907-1908, undated (Box 17, Folder 472)
    - Nolan, James (*), 1895-1896, undated (Box 17, Folder 473)
    - E. P. Noll and Company - J. M. North, 1876-1877, 1881-1882, 1887, undated (Box 17, Folder 474)
    - Northrop, B. G. (*), 1874, 1879-1880, 1882-1883 (Box 18, Folder 475)
    - Northrop, Cyrus - J. S. Norton, 1876, 1882, 1886, 1908, undated (Box 18, Folder 476)
    - Norton, J. Pease (*), 1898-1908 (Box 18, Folder 477)
      See also: American Association for the Advancement of Science, box 1, folder 10
    - Nott, Charles C. - T. Novicowe, 1869, 1876-1877, 1893 (Box 18, Folder 478)
    - Noyes, A. D. (*), 1879-1906 (Box 18, Folder 479)
    - Noyes, Atherton - E. Nye, 1874-1875, 1879, 1884, 1903-1904, undated (Box 18, Folder 480)
    - Oakford, Ellen - Lawrence O'Brien, 1874, 1877, 1879, 1906, undated (Box 18, Folder 481)
    - O'Brien, Mrs. William, undated (Box 18, Folder 482)
    - Ochs, A. - G. K. Olmstead, 1870, 1872-1873, 1875, 1882, 1885-1886, 1888-1890, 1893, 1897, 1901, undated (Box 18, Folder 483)
    - Olmstead, Julia M. (*), 1868-1869 (Box 18, Folder 484)
    - Omart, Henry P. - Rufus M. Overlander, 1871-1873, 1876, 1878, 1883-1885, 1888-1889, 1891-1892, 1895, 1899, 1903, 1908 (Box 18, Folder 485)
    - Owen, Charles H., 1866, 1876, 1882 (Box 18, Folder 486)
    - Owen, Charles W.
    - Owen, Edward T., 1874, 1876, 1886, 1898 (Box 18, Folder 487)
    - Oxley and Enos Manufacturing Company - J. H. Packard, 1876, 1878, 1890, 1899 (Box 18, Folder 488)
    - Packard, Lewis R., 1868-1870, 1872, 1880-1881 (Box 18, Folder 489)
    - Page, James A. - Walter L. Palmer, 1869, 1873, 1882-1883, 1888, 1891, 1895, 1897, 1900, 1906, undated (Box 18, Folder 490)
    - Pardee, John S. - Frank M. Parsons, 1865-1866, 1869, 1877, 1880, 1885-1886, 1889-1891, 1893, 1895, 1897, 1900-1901, undated (Box 18, Folder 491)
    - Parsons, Herbert (*), 1896-1897, 1907 (Box 18, Folder 492)
    - Parsons, Mrs. M. A. - Oliver H. Payne, 1869, 1875, 1877, 1880, 1883-1884, 1886, 1890, 1897-1899, 1908 (Box 18, Folder 493)
    - Payne, R. F., Jr. - Wilfred Peck, 1868, 1873, 1874, 1875, 1882-1886, 1888, 1889, 1890-1891, 1897-1898, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 18, Folder 494)
    - Peck, Willard (*), 1881-1882 (Box 18, Folder 495)
    - Pecker, Clark - Alfred Pell, 1874, 1882, 1888, 1890, undated (Box 18, Folder 496)